Shannon Mettry

shannon-mettry.vercel.app | LinkedIn | GitHub |

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Dedicated and results-driven professional with extensive experience in **revamping and enhancing** user experience complimented by an ability to conduct design research and analyze trends. I am a highly skilled web developer with over **2 years of experience** in **HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React**.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• **Tech Stack:** HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, React

Libraries: Bootstrap, MUI, Materialize

Dev Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Github

Frameworks: React.js, Express, Node.js

Databases: MongoDB

Learning: Flgma, Redux, React Router

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Freelance

Oct 2021 – Present Remote – Madrid, Spain

Location: Madrid, Spain

- Meeting with the prospective clients to review website, and gather the client's specifications for new or existing
 websites
- Designing and implementing the front-end using **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **jQuery**, **React**, **and JavaScript**.
- · Preparing multiple designs and wireframes for clients approval before proceeding with development.

English Professor

Spanish Ministry of Education

Aug 2015 – Present

Spain

- Collaborated with cultural ambassadors aimed at revamping and executing teaching strategies to spread new strategies in different schools.
- Contributed in improving English learning progress by **identifying and developing new teaching methods** and maintaining consistent collaboration with teachers and administration.
- Ensured proper **implementation and success of learning initiatives** in close coordination with teachers and parents.

Auto Claims Adjuster

Infinity Property Casualty Corp

Mar 2015 – Sep 2015 Cerritos, California, USA

- **Saved company and customers thousands of dollars** by establishing and executing strategies for assistance of policyholders.
- Reviewed customers' information, established executive summaries, and presented to team management.

Customer Service Lead Advisor

July 2014 – Mar 2015 Irvine, California, USA

Student Loan Education Center

- Implemented strategic sales management initiatives by updating customer data and generating executive summaries. Maintained integrity of customer databases and mailing lists aimed at promoting customer trust and moral.
- Provided financial aid counselling to customers on their student loans and **made professional judgement decisions** regarding their student loan payment plans, saving customers hundreds of dollars a month.

EDUCATION

University of Carlos III of Madrid

Master of Social Science

Getafe, Madrid, Spain

California State University Fullerton

Bachelor of Sociology

Orange Country, California, USA

PROJECTS

Therapy Career Portfolio

React.js, HTML, CSS, GSAP

Source Code

- Utilized **responsive design** to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on Vercel

Wedding Invitation Website

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, GSAP, SubmitForm

Source Code

- Submit Form, sending guests name and number of guests to client's email
- Accordion with Arrival Details
- Image animation

SunnySide Agency Landing Page

HTML, CSS (SASS), JS

Source Code

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Utilized **responsive design** to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on Vercel

Working Project: Seamstress Store

HTML, CSS, JS

Source Code

- JS Mobile Navigation Toggle Menu
- Utilized Flexbox to format html sections
- Deployed on Vercel

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Placed 3rd for the Group Challenge at the NUWE International All Female Hackathon
- · California State University of Fullerton Dean's Honors List GPA 3.5 or higher
- Awarded the California College **Promise Grant Scholarship**
- · Awarded the Community Service Graduation Cord

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

- Native English
- · Spanish B2